ROHIT KUMAR

Personal website: http://rohit13k.github.io/

(+32) · 465 · 931350 ♦ rohit1308k@gmail.com ♦ Brussels, Belgium Langugaes: English(native fluency), Hindi(native), Spanish(A1)

RESEARCH INTEREST

Big Data platforms, Data Stream Mining, Graph Stream Mining and Distributed Processing, Data Security and Privacy.

SUMMARY

I am an ambitious, enthusiastic and talented individual with a keen eye for detail and a flair for new startups and projects. I have got an opportunity to work on a new initiative and take it from an internal project to a million dollar business. My objective is to work in a challenging work environment and to learn something new every day. I have worked in an Indian IT industry for 6.5 years before moving to Europe to pursue my passion for research and knowledge. Currently, I am pursuing my Ph.D. in "Graph Data stream mining and distributed processing" from ULB(Brussels) and UPC(Barcelona). I have 6 publications in top conferences and 1 granted and 2 applied patents.

WORK EXPERIENCE

ULB
Research Assistant
August 2014 - now
Brussel, Belgium

- · 1 A* rank, 2 A rank and 1 B rank full conference papers published.
- · Working on Graph stream mining algorithms for different use cases influence propagation or fraud detection.
- · Working on Apache GraphX and other Distributed Graph processing systems.

Royal bank of Scotland

June 2014 - July 2014 New Delhi, India

Software Designer

 \cdot Developing high availability query systems on Oracle Coherence.

Tata Consultancy Services

April 2013 - May 2014 Mumbai, India

Assistant Consultant

- · Technical team lead for the development of an Online Assessment software.
- · Client interaction and designing new offerings for education domain.
- · Managed a team of 30 software developers.

Tata Consultancy Services

April 2011 - March 2013

IT Analyst

Mumbai, India

- · Managed the technical aspects of expanding my master's thesis from in house incubation to a million dollar business for TCS.
- · Developed and deployed the complete Eco-system of the online assessment platform in multi-tenant architecture for software as a service model.
- · Managed a team of 10 software developers.

TCS - Tata Research Development and Design Center

April 2011 - September 2011

Researcher

Pune, India

· Worked on data privacy and data security.

Tata Consultancy Services

Assistant System Engineer

Nov 2007 - March 2011 Chennai, India

- · Lead architect to develop and deploy the online assessment platform for TCS hiring throughout India.
- · Performance and Security Lead for the online assessment platform.

JNCSAR, IISC, Bangalore

2004 - 2007

Summer Research Intern

Bangalore, India

· Did two summer(2 months) and one winter(1 month) research intern in Nanoscience.

EDUCATION

Université Libre de Bruxelles (ULB), Belgium & Universitat Politécnica de Catalunya (UPC), Spain August 2014 - Now

- · Joint PhD in Computer Science
- · Research Topic: Graph Stream mining and distributed processing

Chennai Mathematical Institute, India

April 2008 - March 2011

- · M.Sc in Computer Science
- · Thesis Topic: Security aspects of online Assessment platform-Touchstone

Hindu College Delhi University, India

July 2004 - July 2007

· B.Sc(Hons) in Physics

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Java, Scala, C++, R-basics

Databases MySQL, Microsoft SQL, MongoDB, Oracle Coherence

Frameworks Hadoop, Apache Spark, Apache Storm, J2EE, Kafka, Struts 2, JDBC

Tools SVN, CVS, github, Eclipse, RStudio, Octave, Matlab, gnuplot

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- FNRS-Belgian National Funds for Scientific research, Scholarship for Doctoral Research Study.
- Best Technical Lead Award in ACTion2013 in SMB iON, TCS.
- Special initiative Award by TCS in May 2013.
- Technical Excellence Award by TCS in March 2012.
- Innovation of the year award southern region in TATA Innovista 2011.
- Senior Diploma in Arts and Painting from Ankan Kala Bibhag, Ravindra Bharti University in 2006.

PUBLICATIONS AND PATENTS

- IMaxer: A Unified System for evaluating Influence Maximization Mechanisms in Location-based Social Networks.CIKM 2017 (DEMO Paper)
- Finding simple temporal cycles in an interaction network. ECML/PKDD 2017 (Workshop paper)
- Activity-Driven Influence Maximization in Social Networks. ECML/PKDD 2017 (Nectar Track)
- Cost Model for Pregel on GraphX. ADBIS 2017
- Information Propagation in Interaction Networks. EDBT 2017
- Location Influence in Location-based Social Networks. WSDM 2017
- Maintaining Sliding-Window Neighborhood Profiles in Interaction Networks. ECML/PKDD 2015
- System and method for automated competency assessment (US8915744) Granted
- Secured Computer Based Assessment (US20140186812A1) Applied
- Customized question paper generation (US20130084554) Applied